{"tossups": [{"question": "Two characters in this play laugh about crashing their tandem bicycle in Ardenneson the road to Sedan. One character relays a story about a tailor who takes threemonths to make a pair of pants. Another character in this play promises to giveanother the (+) combination to the cupboard in order to \"finish him\". This playopens with a man using a step ladder to look out two windows on opposite sides of the stage, and is later told to put his companion in the exact center of the room after (*) wheeling him \"around the world\". After demanding \"Me pap!\", one character is given a dog biscuit, and later dies inside a garbage can. In addition to Nagg and Nell, this play features a character who cannot stand and another who cannot sit. For ten points, name this play about Hamm and Clov written by Samuel Beckett.", "answer": "Endgame (or Fin de Partie)", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Endgame</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Endgame"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Fin de Partie"}, {"question": "This collection contains a poem promising its title recruit that \"town and fieldwill mind you/ Till Ludlow tower is down\" and another in which the speaker becomes\"a soldier of the Queen\" called The New Mistress. One poem states \"Eyes the shadynight has shut/ Cannot see the (+) record cut\". In another, the speaker confirms theadvice he had gotten not to give his heart away that he had been given a year before. The penultimate poem in this collection posits that (*) \"malt does more than Milton can\" and concludes with a story of Mithridates dying old spoken to a man who \"eat[s his] victuals fast enough\". For ten points, identify this collection containing To an Athlete Dying Young, When I Was One-and-Twenty, and Terence, This is Stupid Stuff written by A. E. Housman.", "answer": "A Shropshire Lad", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>A Shropshire Lad</u></b>", "acceptable": ["A Shropshire Lad"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this short story, Sayre mentions that the story of the Pink Geisha was abouthis brother. The central figure of this short story visits a consulate to ask when therobins nest in the United States. The protagonist breaks a (+) mirror when hermaid suggests she get some beauty sleep, and she has a purple-eyed child named Trouble whose father's name she pronounces as \"Ben-ja-meen Frang-a-leen\". The main character contemplates a life in a castle with a thousand servants when (*) Yamadori proposes, but decides to wait for her husband's return. The title character of this John Luther Long work is found after committing harakiri by her maid Suzuki before a visit by her husband's new American wife. For ten points, name this short story about Lieutenant Pinkerton and Cho-Cho-San that inspired a Puccini opera.", "answer": "Madame Butterfly", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Madame Butterfly</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Madame Butterfly"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this play, the Bishop of Bromley writes in the newspaper calling Christians toassist with the H-bomb. The protagonist of this play calls his wife Lady Pusillanimous.The protagonist and his wife shared an apartment with (+) Hugh Tanner after theirwedding and play a game of bears and squirrels. That wife moves out with the help of her father, Colonel (*) Redfern, but returns after a miscarriage. In the meantime, her husband shacks up with actress Helena Charles. Alison burns her arm while ironing as her husband wrestles with the Welsh boarder Cliff. For ten points, name this modern realist play featuring the tirades of Jimmy Porter written by John Osborne.", "answer": "Look Back in Anger", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Look Back in Anger</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Look Back in Anger"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one play, a character wants to leave one of these events to go watch Modjelewskipitch. That play's first act ends with the protagonist asking \"You don't really meanyou'll kill me, do you?\" During one of these events in another play, one participant isasked (+) \"Do you ever think about the things you do think about?\" A central propused during one of these events is a pawn shop switchblade, and another of these events is covered by Baltimore Herald reporter (*) E.K. Hornbeck. Henry Drummond has to inform Bert Cates that he won this event, after which his opponent Matthew Harrison Brady dies. For ten points, name these events written about by Lawrence and Lee and Reginald Rose in Inherit the Wind and Twelve Angry Men.", "answer": "trial (accept any answer involving a legal proceeding, accept jury deliberation and equivalents until second quoted question)", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>trial</u></b>", "acceptable": ["trial"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept any answer involving a legal proceeding, accept jury deliberation and equivalents until second quoted question"}, {"question": "One character created by this author dreams of himself and his assistant,Aminadab, botching a surgery. Another character of this author threw a bouquet toa girl in a garden only to see it wither in her hand. In that story, (+) Lisabetta showsthe protagonist a secret entrance to a garden in Padua before he notices a purple handprint on his wrist and offers an antidote created by Professor Baglioni. The title object of one of his stories is shaped like a (*) fairy's hand, and that story sees Aylmer treat his new wife Georgianna. The title character from another story walks with a fellow traveller whose cane is likened to a serpent, avoids Goody Cloyse on a path, and sees his wife Faith at a witches' sabbath. For ten points, name this author of The Birthmark, Rappaccini's Daughter, and Young Goodman Brown.", "answer": "Nathaniel Hawthorne                                                                                                                                                                              ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Nathaniel <b><u>Hawthorne</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nathaniel Hawthorne"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poem mentions a photograph of a Mosler safe which \"survived the blast\" inHiroshima. The \"wasp-waisted\" title figures of this poem are said to \"grow slimmerand younger each year\". The writer sees (+) \"drained faces of Negro school-childrenrise like balloons\" from his television. This poem mentions \"Puritan-pumpkin colored girders\" and \"yellow dinosaur (*) steamshovels\" as signs of the construction of a parking garage and ends by comparing cars to fish and claiming \"a savage servility/ slides by on grease\". A central object in this poem is \"propped by a plank\" and \"sticks like a fishbone in the city's throat\". For ten points, name this poem about a Civil War memorial in Boston written by Robert Lowell.", "answer": "For The Union Dead", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>For The Union Dead</u></b>", "acceptable": ["For The Union Dead"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "It is learned that \"this story has a happy ending\" in an italicized chapterintroducing the narrator's children, Nick and Usha. At the end of this novel, thenarrator is interviewed in Tomatl \u0301an, Mexico by a representative of the (+) JapaneseMinistry of Transport. The narrator of this novel, who is named for a swimming pool in Paris, spends a summer in Brazil studying sloths and finds a colony of (*) meerkats on an island fishing for dorados. An orangutan named Orange Juice and a zebra are killed by a hyena. The narrator is a practicing Christian, Muslim, and Hindu and is the son of the keeper of the Pondicherry Zoo, which houses Richard Parker. For ten points, name this novel in which the narrator shares a lifeboat with a tiger, written by Yann Martel.", "answer": "Life of Pi", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Life of Pi</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Life of Pi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protagonist of one of this author's works gives her cousin a watch chain setwith two of her kidney stones, and a different protagonist projects Mickey Mouse andPopeye reels for a hospital ward. In one novella by this author, rumors of a murder arestarted by a character who suffers from three-day malaria named (+) Merlie Ryan. Acharacter in a novel by this author quits school to work at Woolworth's, has sex with Harry Minowitz, and scares her brother Bubber into running away after he shot Baby Wilson in the head. In addition to (*) Mick Kelly, this author wrote of a woman who lost a fight with her former husband of ten days, Marvin Macy, after the intervention of Cousin Lymon. For ten points, name this author who wrote of Miss Amelia Evans and the deaf-mute John Singer in The Ballad of the Sad Cafe and The Heart is a Lonely Hunter.", "answer": "Carson McCullers", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Carson <b><u>McCullers</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Carson McCullers"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel is found in Ceylon only able to say \"Credo in unumDeum omnipotentem\" and \"shuttle-cock\". The title character tries to comfort a younggirl on a train in an episode known as the Kilsyte case. The wife of the narratorcommits suicide with (+) prussic acid from a vial she had told her husband was fullof heart medicine. The title character visits Luther's protest while staying with his wife at (*) Nauheim; he was there while letting his house at Branshaw Teleragh to recover his losses from Monte Carlo, including a costly affair with La Dolciquita. This novel opens \"This is the saddest story I have ever heard\" and ends with the title character's suicide when his mistress, Nancy Rufford, leaves for India. For ten points, name this novel about Edward Ashburnham written by Ford Madox Ford.", "answer": "The Good Soldier: A Tale of Passion", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Good Soldier: A Tale of Passion</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Good Soldier: A Tale of Passion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One poem titled for these objects states \"We, masters and apprentices both, hideour hearts/ In vain\" and asks \"What use are poets in times of need?\". In separateodes, Pablo Neruda described one of these objects as having \"purple feet\" and \"topazblood\" and told the other \"you duplicate/ the mother's/ rounded womb\". A poemnamed for these two items states (+) \"Thebes and Athens are fading\", sets a scene of asleeping city to claim that \"the kindness of exalted Night is wonderful\", and concludes that life is a dream about gods in uniting Greek mythology with Christianity. In one famous (*) quatrain, these title objects of an elegy by Friedrich Holderlin were enjoyed \"With a Book of Verses underneath the Bough\" with \"Thou\". For ten points, name these food items coming in jugs and loaves in Omar Khayyam's Rubaiyat.", "answer": "bread and wine (both parts required, accept in either order)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>bread and wine</u></b>", "acceptable": ["bread and wine"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "both parts required, accept in either order"}, {"question": "In one novel, an organization attempting this action tempts a man with a firingsquad and a gallows before naming him their leader. In another novel, a group tryingto perform this action adopted the motto \"Springfield, Enfield, throw 'em in thecornfield!\" One group based at Jefferson College in Waco plans to use a festival at(+) Galveston to achieve this feat, which another group is helped a group based in Rivington, North Carolina called America Will Break. This action is advocated by the title group in a novel about (*) Bernard Belgrave and Belton Piedmont written by Sutton Griggs, Imperium in Imperio, and by an Andries-Rhoodie-led group of time-traveling South Africans. For ten points, name this action achieved in Harry Turtledove's Guns of the South by the Confederacy when it used AK-47s to capture Washington D.C.", "answer": "seceding from the United States (accept equivalents, accept starting or winning a Civil War)", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>seceding from the United States</u></b>", "acceptable": ["seceding from the United States"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept equivalents, accept starting or winning a Civil War"}, {"question": "This work uses spilling betel juice on women in the market as an example ofunfriendliness. The driver of a rubbish van in this work abandoned his vehicle justbefore it was destroyed. The action begins when the narrator discovers a black mandead with his face in the mud and the skin stripped off of his back. A lost (+) mahoutis the only one capable of dealing with a particular case of must. A crowd of two thousand people follow the narrator along a road to a confrontation which is carried out so that he can \"avoid looking like a (*) fool\". That narrator had initially headed to the bazaar with his .44 Winchester to scare the title creature, but later borrowed a more powerful gun. For ten points, name this essay in which a Burmese police officer puts down a pachyderm, written by George Orwell.", "answer": "Shooting an Elephant", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Shooting an Elephant</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Shooting an Elephant"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this work, one character touches his eyebrow to feel for his new lover's mole.Another character in this work tears up a letter he had dictated for Marta when hisroommate agrees to help bathe him. That character had used a shirt to clean up aftera bout of diarrhea, refusing to go to the (+) infirmary because drugs are used toweaken political adversaries. Visits from that character's mother are used as a front to plan his poisoning with the warden. One character passes time by telling a (*) story of a boy, an architect, and Irena, who has nightmares about a panther woman, that he had seen in a movie. This work, a play based on the author's novel of the same name, was set in Villa Devoto Prison in Buenos Aires. For ten points, name this play about the cellmates Valentin and Molina written by Manuel Puig.", "answer": "The Kiss of the Spider Woman (or El beso de la mujer aran \u0303a)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Kiss of the Spider Woman</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Kiss of the Spider Woman"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or El beso de la mujer aran \u0303a"}, {"question": "One character in this short story is arrested for dropping a piece of cloth off ofSt. Isaac's Bridge. The protagonist of this story is denied an advertisement becauseof its similarity to a satirical missing dog report and later writes an accusatory letterto (+) Mrs. Podtochin, whom he claims wants him to marry her daughter. The titlecharacter of this story wears the plumed hat and gold-embroidered uniform of a state councilor and the protagonist is a (*) College Assessor who goes by the title Major. The title character is apprehended with a fraudulent passport in a Riga stagecoach, and was earlier found by Ivan Yakovlevich in a morning roll and recognized as belonging to Kovalyov. For ten points, name this short story by Nikolai Gogol about the adventures of the title body part.", "answer": "The Nose", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Nose</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Nose"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this novel, a story is told of 30 men being killed for preferring nitrate fertilizerto potash. This novel's protagonist is secretly slipped a message from his barber to\"die in silence\". The protagonist is denied breakfast due to a (+) toothache, and hasthat tooth fixed without anaesthetic by imagining burning his hand with a cigarette. The last section of this work is titled \"Grammatical Fiction\", while the first three are named for (*) hearings. The protagonist spends most of his time thinking about his former secretary Arlova and pacing six and a half steps at a time. He uses the quadratic alphabet to tap messages to his neighbor, a man known only as 402. Gletkin replaces Ivanov as inquisitor in, for ten points, which novel about the imprisonment of Rubashov written by Arthur Koestler?", "answer": "Darkness at Noon (or Sonnenfinsternis)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Darkness at Noon</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Darkness at Noon"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Sonnenfinsternis"}, {"question": "In one story in this collection, a character gets a job as a correspondence artteacher by fraudulently claiming to be related to Daumier. In another story, thenarrator is impressed by Mary Hudson's baseball prowess while playing with the (+)Comanches. During an interview with Nicholson, a child in this collection predicts his death in a ship's swimming pool, and another child tells of the death of her imaginary friend Jimmy Jimoreeno. The opening story of this collection, which contains (*) Teddy, ends with Muriel napping in her hotel room and her husband returning from a day at the beach and shooting himself in the head. For ten points, name this collection containing Uncle Wiggily in Connecticut, A Perfect Day for Bananafish, and seven others written by J.D. Salinger.", "answer": "Nine Stories", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nine Stories</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nine Stories"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this story sits in a back-drawing room, in which a priest hadrecently died, with his hands pressed together repeating \"O love! O love!\". Thatnarrator frequently lays on the floor of his front parlour to peek out the bottom of thewindow at his love interest. In this story, (+) Mrs. Mercer departs at eight o'clock onSaturday night, although it is still another hour before the narrator's uncle arrives. The main action of the story is set in place when the narrator is told of a retreat at his love interest's (*) convent. The narrator looks at jars at a porcelain stall, but the young lady running it is too busy flirting with two gentlemen, and so he does not actually buy a gift for Mangan's sister. For ten points, name this short story from James Joyce's Dubliners about a title bazaar.", "answer": "Araby", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Araby</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Araby"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One work by this poet is the source of the idiom the \"the spirits that I called\".In another poem, this author wrote of the narrator riding a horse to a nighttimetryst that ended with a tearful departure at sunrise, concluding \"to be so loved,what gladness!/ To love, o Gods, what happiness!\". This man wrote the command(+) \"Flow! Flow onward/.../ Toward the pool in current gushing\" and another instructing to listen only to their master. One character by this author of (*) Welcome and Farewell promises that his daughters will provide tender care and that he will \"play such games\" on a flowered beach. This author of The Sorcerer's Apprentice wrote of a child riding on a windy night dying after being bewitched by the title sprite. For ten points, name this German Romantic poet of The Erlking.", "answer": "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Johann Wolfgang von <b><u>Goethe</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Johann Wolfgang von Goethe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character murders a man impersonating Fatimah the Devotee. This charactersells gold plates and a silver tray to a Jewish merchant before learning that they areworth seventy times as much. This character is unable to climb stairs due to beingweighed down by (+) glass fruit in his pockets, after which he is trapped undergroundby a man pretending to be his uncle. This man ordered the overnight-building of a pavillion and the nighttime disruption of the princess's (*) marriage to the Wazir's son. This son of a tailor, who is deceived by a Maghrabi from Morocco, holds parades showering the audience with gold and watches the Lady Badr al-Budur enter the baths in spite of an order by the Sultan. For ten points, name this character who marries the princess after finding a \"wonderful lamp\" in Arabian Nights.", "answer": "Aladdin", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Aladdin</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Aladdin"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}